Andrew Gallop

Software Engineer \cdot (817) 734.2510 \cdot and rew.ryan.gallop@gmail.com \cdot New York, NY https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-gallop/ \cdot github.com/ndrewgallup/

About Me

I am a Software Engineer and a professional actor with a passion for merging the world of tech and entertainment through awareness, sincerity, and creativity.

I am naturally creative and curious. I use my 15+ years of arts experience to navigate user/company needs, to joyfully collaborate, and to resiliently produce work that is relevant and lasting.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python | **Libraries and Frameworks** - React, Node.js, Express.js **Database** - PostgreSQL, Sequelize, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM | **Other** - RESTful Routing JSON

Software Development Projects

Mancala - Browser-based game modeled after the classic marble board game.

02/2022

HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, Bootstrap

- Implemented Javascript functions to execute determined game logic.
- Styled and created all visual aspects using HTML5 and CSS3 to present a unique design.
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment to display process.

UpBeat - Platform for posting favorite music albums and sharing music reviews.

03/2022

MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose, EJS

- Utilized a MEN stack to build a full stack application with full CRUD and implemented RESTful routing calls.
- Implemented a multi-schema database using MongoDB and Mongoose with a one-to-many schema design.
- Wireframed and planned UI design of application using Whimsical and Trello.
- Implemented Google OAuth to protect user identity and contributions.

Pilot - A React application that connects open water swimmers to pilots and new open water.

04/2022

- Utilized a decoupled MERN stack to build a full stack React application with full CRUD and implemented RESTful routing calls.
- Acted as Github Manager to oversee contributions amongst all team members to keep code current and dry.
- Implemented a multi-schema database using MongoDB and Mongoose with various relational schema design.
- Implemented JWT Auth to protect user identity and contributions.

Professional Experience

86 Logic, Co-Editor

01/2021 - Present

- Evaluated thousands of submissions for publication that cultivated a global literary community based around the hospitality industry.
- Utilized expert communication to effectively manage multiple projects simultaneously while monitoring various budgets, priorities, and deadlines.

Actor's Equity Association, Actor

03/2017 - Present

• Analyzed the artistic vision of various playwrights and filmmakers by engaging in designer meetings and producer conferences in order to understand project trajectory.

- Utilized critical listening, intentional communication, and transparent collaboration skills daily in order to seamlessly execute a creative process from start to finish.
- Implemented the artistic vision of various projects that often led to stakeholder driven Broadway runs and appearances in the film-festival circuit.

UC, San Diego, Supervisor/Instructor-Undergraduate Acting/Public Speaking

09/2016 - 03/2018

- Educated undergraduate students in the basics of voice, movement, and acting, for which I received an Excellence in Teaching Award.
- Fostered a collaborative and inclusive environment in which students could fearlessly take creative risks, succeed happily, and fail joyfully.
- Supervised each course by coordinating with the faculty chair, enhancing curriculum, conducting weekly meetings with other instructors, and evaluating their work in the classroom.

Zerrer Chiropractic, Personal Assistant

05/2016 - 12/2016

- Overhauled and enhanced the existing method for storing patient information that offered the doctor increased quality time with patients.
- Oversaw patient-to-doctor communication, check-in/check-out policies, and accounts in order to standardize the overall positive energy of the office.

Education

General Assembly | Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

University of California | San Diego, California

Masters of Fine Arts in Acting

2018

University of Oklahoma | Norman, Oklahoma

Bachelors of Fine Arts in Musical Theater

2015